We use moral persuasion,
and then we barbecue them.
Are you going to personally prosecute
the case against Nicholas Baron?
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Hello?
All we want is justice.
Whenever I find who's responsible
for endangering my daughter,
I'm gonna feed him to the District
Attorney piece by piece.
- Could be disbarred for this.
- You were saying?
--by the homecoming
of Nicholas Baron,
the reputed gangland leader known
sometimes as ''The Baron, ''
who was paroled yesterday
after seven years in prison.
Turn that up.
--extortion to conspiracy
to commit murder.
Baron was convicted only
of tax evasion,
but his imprisonment was enough,
authorities say,
to loosen the grip the Baron family
had on organised crime
operations in this area.
Advanced age and failing health
were reportedly factors in his release.
- Don't wait up for me.
- Baron is 65.
On the local weather front--
- Why don't you just take my car?
- Forget it!
Donald!
Jesus.
Sarah? Sarah?
Damn. No, not you.
Something in the air is playing havoc
with my nose.
Hay fever.
You take what?
I see. So the idea is
the pills make you so sleepy
you forget you got hay fever.
Well, if I find somewhere to lie down,
I'll take one of them.
Tell Charlene I'll be there
in a few minutes. Okay.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
That's all right. Actually, Mr. Matlock,
I was waiting for you.
- Here.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you.
My name is Paul Baron.
My father's Nicholas Baron.
Somebody planted a car bomb
in Donald Kovacs' car this morning.
He's dead. The police think
my father killed him,
but he didn't do it.
But he would like to talk with you.
I'm sure Nicholas Baron
has lots of lawyers
with far more experience
in this sort of thing than I.
He wants you.
- Well, thanks, but I decline.
- No, it's all right. I've got plenty.
You talk with my father,
and whether or not you decide
to take the case, this is what you get.
- That's $20,000.
- That's what it says.
You wanna go for a ride?
Air conditioned?
I'll have to run it full blast.
My father's right over there.
Know anything about roses,
Mr. Matlock?
Oh, a fair amount. I know you're
supposed to fertilise them,
water them, and cut them.
That's more than most people know.
This is a cultivar that I personally
helped to develop.
I call it Irene's Ruby.
Roses are a hobby
that became a business.
I know a fair amount about you too,
Mr. Matlock.
Born in some backwater town
that doesn't even exist anymore,
poor family,
father killed in a car crash,
and here you are, one of
the best-known lawyers in the country.
Now, how do you explain that?
Hard work.
I believe it was pre-ordained.
I think you simply followed along
the path that had been laid out for you,
just like I followed along the path
that had been laid out for me.
Looking back along that path,
I can see some things
I regret having done.
Some of the crimes that I did
I've already paid for in prison.
All of the others I'll pay for
soon enough,
but I did not murder
Donald Kovacs,
and I refuse to pay
for the crimes of others.
It's a matter of honour.
I should return this.
I don't charge for consultations.
As for the case, I decline.
Mr. Matlock,
I'm gonna do something
I've never done before.
I'm gonna beg.
Please clear my name.
I didn't do this,
and I want to stand trial
so people will know that.
I want to do it soon
because in about six months' time,
I'm gonna be dead.
Please, Mr. Matlock.
On one condition.
The case will be handled my way
on my terms.
I make all the decisions,
and I take it all the way,
no matter what.
All the way, no matter what,
or I'm out right now.
You have my word.
The first thing you're gonna do
is turn yourself in.
All right. Anybody wanna
do the honours?
Miranda him, Charlie,
then book him.
All right, Frank. What have you got
on my client?
Motive.
Donald Kovacs was the man who,
according to your client,
bribed the accountant whose testimony
sent him to prison.
He's also the man who took over
many of the Baron family's
illegitimate enterprises
while said client was in prison.
What's the matter?
- I got a hay fever going.
- It's all right.
We got Eddie A.
Eddie Alonzo, the man
who made the bomb,
and indeed planted the bomb
that killed Kovacs.
Now, Eddie A. was an old friend
of the Baron family.
I say was because
he's no longer with us.
He was found shot to death
in a field this morning.
Two bullets to the head.
Now, the phrase that comes to mind
is ''gangland-style killing.''
Hey, but what are friends for?
Now, we got mud from that field
found embedded in the tyres
of a certain car.
Could we get on
to the substantial part?
No problem, because we got
an eyewitness
who saw the driver of that certain car
shoot and kill Eddie Alonzo.
We've also got this,
found at the scene of the crime,
and this belongs to--
Guess who.
Frank, do you really think my client
would murder his own friend?
Come on, Counsellor.
I think your client would murder
his own mother
if it meant saving his hide.
The Barons aren't a family.
They're a pack of wolves.
- Here I am defending the head wolf.
- Right. But why?
I don't know, Frank.
I guess I'm just living right.
Phillips, I can't get
a conviction on this turkey
unless the wife will testify
that she saw him pull the trigger.
If those detectives of yours spent
less time staring out their windows
and more time chasing criminals,
we could put a few more
of them away, couldn't we?
Don't tell me how tough it is.
I was a cop, remember?
Will you stop trying
to break my heart
and get me some hard evidence?
I don't care how you do it,
just get it!
Are you as pleased with yourself
as you look?
- Here's the goods on Nicholas Baron.
- Sit down.
How long has your father
been governor?
You know, if you'd have asked
before you helped yourself,
I might have warned you.
Max? He's almost deaf. Max!
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
No, no, don't move.
I'll toss them to you.
There, two...
...and two more. Okay?
You're a good boy, Max.
I love you.
His hearing's really getting bad.
Tell me something.
What do you think
of the Baron case?
- I think it's a lock, boss.
- So do I.
I'm afraid you're gonna have to
take a back seat this time, Palmer.
But who's gonna prosecute?
I said when I became
District Attorney
that I would break the back
of organised crime in this city,
and this is part of that promise.
Are you saying that you're going to
personally prosecute
- the case against Nicholas Baron?
- That's exactly what I'm saying.
You and Ben Matlock almost
came to blows
last time y'all
met in a courtroom.
I never listen to rumours.
Is it true that you and District Attorney
McShane are bitter enemies?
Well, let's just say I didn't vote for him.
Excuse me.
Defendant waives time.
Further reading of the indictment
pleads not guilty.
May we proceed directly
to the issue of bail?
Mr. McShane,
what is the state's position?
We recommend the defendant be held
without bail until his trial.
To free a man with his reputation
as a mobster,
one who faces
two counts of murder,
would be a slap in the face
of every law-abiding citizen
in this community.
Moreover, Nicholas Baron is a man
of considerable wealth and means,
one who could, and I submit would,
flee at the first opportunity.
I move that he remain in custody
till the time of his trial.
Your Honour, my client
has no intention of fleeing.
On the contrary,
he wants to stand trial,
and he wants to do so
as soon as possible.
No matter what his past,
no matter what his reputation,
he's entitled to the rights
of any citizen.
Your Honour, the parole board
of the state penitentiary
saw fit to grant my client
an early release.
They didn't see him
as a threat to society,
they saw him as an ageing ill man
deserving pity.
Surely the court of the people
is no less compassionate.
Bail is set at $500,000.
Preliminary hearing
is set for September 1 2th.
Is that acceptable to the defence?
Yes, Your Honour.
- Mr. McShane?
- Prosecution agrees.
Court will recess
till 2:30 this afternoon.
Never thought I'd see you
in a courtroom again.
Never thought I'd have
an opportunity like this.
Is it true that you and District Attorney
McShane are bitter enemies?
- Let's just say I didn't vote for him.
- Do you wanna elaborate on that?
- How do I look?
- Oh, you look great.
Your client looks suspiciously
like a gangster.
- Bless you.
- Thank you.
Whatever it is you're allergic to,
I sure hope it isn't flowers.
Seems Nicholas Baron's friends,
or business associates, you might say,
are delighted
to have you on their team.
You, I take it, are not.
I was under the impression
we were criminal lawyers, Dad,
not criminals' lawyers.
I understand. I'll take this one alone.
I just wanna know why
you took the case.
Nicholas Baron
has his own lawyers.
He could've gone anywhere,
but he came to me.
I have to believe it's because
I have a reputation for being honest.
Besides, he begged me.
He begged me
to take this thing to trial.
It was very hard for him.
Try as I might,
I can't get around that.
I just can't get around it.
He wants an honest defence,
I have to give him the best that I can.
If you're in, so am I.
I'll see you at 1 1 :00
at the Baron estate.
All right.
Hey, Ben.
Ben, you'll never guess what I heard
about you down at the police station.
Does it have anything to do with
my being Nicholas Baron's lawyer?
- You're kidding.
- Guess again.
He's not kidding.
Tyler, we need you to check out
an Edward Alonzo.
Apparently, he's the man
who put the bomb in Kovacs' car.
He's known on the streets
as Eddie A.
- We're talking major underworld here.
- Well, better get started.
I'm Ben Matlock.
I have an appointment.
Hello. I could've told you you'd wind up
taking the case. I'm Cathy Baron.
Turn around and place
your hands on the--
Leave him, Marty.
This is Benjamin Matlock,
Father's attorney.
Come in, please.
I guess everybody's a little nervous.
I'm searching everything
that moves.
It's my brother Paul's idea.
How many times do I have to tell you?
You didn't walk today, did you?
I had other things to worry about
this morning.
Mr. Matlock. Welcome.
I'd like you to meet
my younger son, Daniel.
- You're a doctor?
- Internist.
You know, I've been having
an awful problem
with hay fever lately.
I don't suppose you--
I'm sorry.
I only prescribe for patients.
The cardiologist is gonna
stop by this afternoon.
- You'll be here?
- No.
I have other patients too,
you know.
- Nice meeting you.
- Same here.
I thought this little get-together
was gonna involve the whole family.
Some of us are more interested
in family business than others.
Then again, some of us
are just not welcome.
- How are you, Mr. Matlock?
- Fine.
Did you talk to the D.A.?
Yeah, and he says
he has an eyewitness
who saw you shoot Eddie Alonzo.
- That's impossible. I was in the park.
- Well, we need to cover all bases.
Right now, in order to plant the seed
of reasonable doubt,
we need to give some thought as to
who else might have killed him.
Hi. Sorry to be late.
Having car trouble lately
and had to take a taxi.
Nicholas, Paul,
this is my daughter and partner,
- Charlene Matlock.
- How do you do?
- Nicholas and Paul Baron.
- It's a pleasure.
Please.
- May I?
- By all means.
- Anyone else?
- I'll have some. Thank you.
Let me go ahead with this.
Because the killer had access
to Nicholas' car and gun,
he or she was probably
no stranger to this household.
What are you saying?
Just that I'd like
to have a word or two
with your help
and any business associates
who might come by often.
No.
Mr. Matlock,
we take care of our own here.
That's why our associates--
Well, the family business
over the past several years
has been reduced
to a small trucking company,
and we're talking to our employees.
That's not entirely accurate.
- It's not?
- No.
Besides owning
the trucking company,
you also have partial ownership
in three restaurants,
five country clubs,
two refuse-removal companies,
and a host of flower shops.
Sugar?
No, no sugar.
And that's true, by the way.
We have a few minor
legitimate diversifications.
There is one thing about this case
that bothers me.
The man who killed Kovacs
and then was himself killed,
Eddie Alonzo,
was someone
whom all of you knew.
Of course we knew him.
He was one of my father's
oldest employees.
He bounced all three of us
on his knee.
Are you saying that one of us
hired him and then had him killed?
He was like a brother to me,
like a second father to the children.
- Besides, he was retired.
- I know.
But who could best
talk him out of retiring?
I don't think a stranger.
I think someone
he knew and trusted.
Well, if you'll excuse us,
we'll go to work.
- Let's get a line on the eyewitness.
- Could I see you for a minute, please?
I'll see you outside.
Anything you have to say to
Mr. Matlock, you say in front in me.
- Well?
- I want him off this case.
I've been against hiring an outsider
from the beginning
and nothing he has said or done
has made me change my mind on that.
You've made your point, Paul,
but I'm going to ignore it.
Mr. Matlock is my lawyer,
and that's the way it's going to be.
- Cathy? You must be Cathy Baron.
- Must I?
I've seen your picture in the
newspaper. Charlene Matlock.
- I'm working on your father's case.
- Hello.
For the moment, I'm without wheels.
Can I get a ride into town?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
Tell my dad I have a lift.
- Don't forget your seat belt.
- Thanks.
- Do you always drive this fast?
- Sorry.
That's all right.
So you're a successful lawyer.
I'm envious.
Right now, I'm just a successful junior
partner, but I'm working on it.
That's a lovely locket.
Is it old?
It's my mother's.
God, it feels good
to get out of that house.
Still live at home?
When Nicholas Baron is your father,
you don't exactly have
a whole lot of options in life.
- I'll give you a perfect example.
- What?
- Do you see that cop up there?
- Yeah.
Okay.
See what I mean?
I can't even get a cop interested in me.
It's very limiting.
- That's tough.
- So how's the case going?
- Well, it's a little early to speculate.
- Please do.
All right.
Whoever killed Eddie Alonzo had to
have access to your father's house.
You mean like one of us.
We can't rule that out.
You'd better learn one thing fast,
and that's no matter what,
we are a family here,
and no outsider dare question
our loyalty to each other ever.
I can understand that, Cathy.
Like you have to understand
that we're not on the case
to protect your family.
We're here
to defend your father.
Now, do I still get a ride
or do I have to walk?
Okay, you're right. We're even,
but hang on.
Tyler? Tyler, it's me, Ben.
For crying out loud,
what are you expecting?
Eddie Alonzo's ghost?
Somebody killed him,
and that somebody might be looking
for somebody who knew him,
and I am here in his apartment.
- Did you find anything?
- Yeah.
I found some escrow papers.
Eddie Alonzo bought himself
a house ten days ago.
A house?
Sounds like he came
into some money recently.
You think that money
came from the hit?
I don't know.
Nicholas Baron and Eddie Alonzo
go back almost 50 years.
I don't think the Baron
would have to pay him.
What a guy.
Now can we get out of here?
I'll tell you what to do.
See if you can find some current
pictures of the Baron's children.
Maybe somebody in this building
saw them with Eddie Alonzo recently.
Okay.
You were saying?
We're dealing with
professional criminals here.
The Baron and his family,
the victim and his family--
I mean, these guys are all pros.
And I'll bet you that
that sniper was, too.
If he was such a pro,
why am I still alive?
Because nine times out of ten,
Kovacs wanted
to scare you off the case.
A case you had no business
being on in the first place.
- Want some coffee?
- No.
See, they're all afraid that you're
gonna see to it that this guy walks
and that the old man just might try
and recoup a few
of the business losses the family
suffered while he was in prison.
Yeah. The trucking company
did go downhill, didn't it?
The trucking company?
Come on, these guys
are into numbers.
They're into so many rackets,
they can't even keep track of them.
And now the word is
that the Baron has some
moral objections to dealing in dope.
Give me a break.
I'll tell you what happened.
The Kovacs cornered the market first
and then muscled them out, and if
Donald Kovacs had had any smarts,
he would've stopped there. But no,
he got greedy and they got even.
If that's the case,
the Kovacs had to expect
some kind of reprisal
when the old man got out.
They probably did, but they didn't
expect the reprisal so soon.
Well, I guess the best thing
for me to do
is go over there and have
a talk with them.
The Kovacs?
I'll call the coroner and have him
keep an eye out for you.
Talk to the Kovacs.
Now, that's the way azaleas
are supposed to look.
What kind of fertiliser do you use?
What'd you say?
I said fertiliser.
What kind do you use?
A little of this, a little of that.
Trade secret, huh?
- Mr. Matlock, come in. Phil Kovacs.
- Thank you. Nice house.
Beautiful grounds.
I was asking your gardener
how he does it.
I didn't get very far.
Well, he does have a little problem
with his hearing.
A problem with his hearing
or a problem with trying
to be something he isn't?
No harm in having someone
keep an eye out front.
- Yes. Is Mrs. Kovacs here?
- No.
You did indicate that
you wanted to talk with me.
Can I offer you a drink?
What's your pleasure?
Maybe a glass of mineral water.
I understand you used to help
your brother run his business.
- Sort of second in command.
- That's right.
Any idea who
might have taken a shot
at my associate and me
this afternoon?
Took a shot at you?
Absolutely not.
Why would we do that?
If somebody frightened me
off this case,
nobody else worth a damn
will take it.
Nicholas Baron would be convicted.
I think you'd like that.
You know, I heard prison
got to the old man.
Made him soft.
If I had to guess,
I'd say it was his son.
Paul?
He'd like nothing better
than to start a war with us.
It's the only prayer he's got of
getting back in the major leagues.
- Like you say, it's only a guess.
- That's why we want you on the case.
To prove the Baron innocent,
you gotta find out who's guilty.
What happens to the individual?
All we want is justice.
Hello, Mr. Matlock.
You said you only prescribe
for patients. I'm a patient.
Hay fever's worse than ever.
- Something you get every year?
- No, first time.
My nose is running,
my eyes is watery,
the back of my throat itches.
I'm sneezing constantly.
- It's driving me crazy.
- Say:
You should be seeing an allergist,
not me.
I thought I'd throw business
your way.
From the looks of your waiting room,
you could use it.
Well,
having Nicholas Baron for a father
is not exactly good for business.
Having him for a client
isn't good for business, either.
It took me five years to build up
a practise
and one day for my father
to destroy it.
I'm gonna give you a shot.
I'll need a hip.
- You think your father's guilty?
- I think he was framed.
I do too.
- By somebody in our family?
- Maybe.
Just for the record, it's an allegation
I deeply resent.
I can tell.
- These just came.
- Take them to the children's hospital.
These are for Charlene.
- Thank you.
- Who are they from?
Paul Baron.
I'm having dinner with him tonight.
So I can interview him.
Edward Alonzo.
According to one of the tellers
at his bank, the only thing
Edward Alonzo has deposited
in the last nine years
is his social security cheques.
But guess what happened
last week?
He walked in with a cashier's cheque.
$25,000, which he withdrew
the very next day
and used it as a down payment
on a house for his sister.
Early tomorrow morning,
I want you to go down to the park
where Nicholas Baron walks.
See if you can find somebody
who saw him there that morning.
Okay.
Well, the only way
we'll get this case dismissed
is to discredit the D.A.'s eyewitness,
and the only way to do that
is to get an eyewitness of our own.
Relax, Ben. It's only an interview.
That'll be all. Thank you.
Hello. Look at you.
Don't you look nice.
- Have a seat.
- Thank you.
That's a very pretty dress.
- You have nice taste.
- Thank you.
They closed the doors tonight
at my request.
I wanted to spare you any
embarrassment
you might feel by being seen
with me socially.
I also find the idea of
dining with you alone irresistible.
How nice.
So here's to a mutually
useful evening.
How's your father?
Convinced your father's innocent.
How's yours?
Convinced your father
can get him off.
Well, that was simple.
So much for business.
You know what I think?
We should start off with the scampi,
and then move right into the veal.
They've got a great veal dish here.
It's their speciality.
I hate to interrupt the festivities
with anything as mundane as the case,
but we do need
a little bit more to go on.
- We do?
- Yeah.
- Like what?
- Well...
- What about the Kovacs family?
- What about them?
Could any one of them murdered
Donald Kovacs or Eddie Alonzo?
- Any one of them.
- How do we prove that?
Well, first, we have to get one
of them to confess.
I don't think I wanna
know how you do that.
Charlene, first, we talk.
We're reasonable.
We use moral persuasion,
and then we barbecue them.
You're a dangerous man.
That sounds
almost like a compliment.
It is.
Almost.
- What?
- I have some questions
about your family enterprises.
Fill that out and send it
over to the office.
That way I won't have to ask them
over dinner.
I have to tell you I'm really not
in the mood for scampi or veal.
Could I see a menu, please?
Dad?
- Hello?
- Place is a mess, isn't it?
- Who--?
- You should see your father.
We're at the courthouse.
The side door's open.
- And come alone.
- Who is--?
Dad?
Hello?
Sorry to wake you up,
but there's an emergency
down at the courthouse.
That's where I'm holding
your daughter.
Charlene?
Hello?
- Hello?
- Try your office.
- Charlene?
- Dad?
Are you all right?
- I'm all right. Are you all right?
- I got this phone call.
- Hello?
- This is just a game.
Walk off this case
while you still can walk.
Somebody really wants us
off this case.
Somebody's trying to scare us
Let me tell you something.
Now, I don't care who it is.
Anything, I mean anything
happens to my daughter,
there's gonna be hell to pay.
- Our men will find out who did it.
- Paul, please.
He's here because
he thinks it's one of us.
That's impossible.
Isn't Phillip Kovacs
the one you should be harassing?
Let me tell you something.
Whenever I find who's responsible
for endangering my daughter,
I'm gonna feed him to the District
Attorney piece by piece.
I don't know, Dad.
Call it intuition,
call it pre-hearing jitters,
call it common sense,
but I have this awful feeling
the D.A.'s gonna eat you alive.
You mean it or you trying
to make me feel better?
Dad, he has an eyewitness.
You have nothing.
What are we gonna use
for a defence?
- I wish I knew.
- Mr. Miracle.
I want you to remember
this moment.
Years from now, when you look back
on this time, when you're old
and when you are a graceful matron
with 30 grandchildren,
when criminal historians
study this case,
I want you to remember this time,
when things looked utterly dismal
and absolutely hopeless.
I want you to remember the time
that Tyler Hudson single-handedly
reached in and pulled your
fat out of the fire.
Come in, Alice.
Ben Matlock, Charlene Matlock,
Alice Jenkins.
Alice was in Lincoln Park
panting a landscape
on the very day and at the very time
the murders were committed.
Guess who else was there.
Nicholas Baron. She saw him,
and she's willing to say so in court.
Alice, I am very happy to meet you.
Now, Miss Jenkins,
do I understand correctly
that you've been working
on this painting every day
at Jackson Park for almost
two weeks now?
Yes. You see, that is a study
in the way the sun displays
and enhances these leaves
and the mist on the water.
I intend to call this Sun Dance.
It's nice.
Have you ever seen
Nicholas Baron before?
Yes. As a matter of fact,
I saw him in Jackson Park
because he walked in front of me
when I was painting
on a week ago Wednesday.
He was so handsome
and distinguished,
I had to stop painting.
How far away from you was he?
Nine feet.
- About what time of day was this?
- Close to 8:00.
I was almost done for the day.
That's about the time Mr. Henderson
said that Mr. Alonzo was shot.
- Is this what you wanted?
- I'll let you know.
You sure that's the man you saw?
Yes, yes, because I saw his picture
in one of those
newsweekly magazines.
- And I said to myself:
- Yeah.
''That's that handsome man,
and he just got out of prison.''
So you're sure
that it was Nicholas Baron
that walked in front of you while
you were painting in Jackson Park
on the morning of the 1 9th
around 8:00?
Oh, yes. I'm sure.
I will never forget it.
No further questions.
Miss Jenkins, do you know a man
by the name of Michael Escott?
No.
What about Anthony Berinni?
- No.
- Irrelevant, Your Honour.
Mr. McShane is confusing the witness,
and frankly, confusing me.
I intend to show relevance
in a moment, Your Honour.
Proceed.
Miss Jenkins, do you
know a Robert Daily?
- No.
- You don't?
Well, that's odd.
I say that because according to this
Atlanta police record,
you do know them,
or at least you did.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Isn't it true that these three men were
each charged with serious felonies,
but in each case you came forward
and provided alibis.
Isn't it true, Miss Jenkins,
that in fact you were paid
in each of these instances
to provide an alibi?
- I just like to help people.
- Just answer the question.
Did you see Nicholas Baron in the park
the morning of the 1 9th?
Well--
Just a simple declarative sentence,
Miss Jenkins.
- Tell the truth for a change.
- Your Honour?
Did someone approach you
to be a witness for the defence
in the case?
Yes.
Were you told to testify that you saw
Nicholas Baron in that park?
- Yes.
- You lied, didn't you?
I mean, you never saw him there,
did you?
No.
Did someone pay you to lie,
Miss Jenkins?
Yes.
Would you point him out, please?
- The lawyer, Mr. Matlock.
- I beg your pardon?
The lawyer, Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Matlock?
I have no further use
for this witness.
- Matlock could be disbarred for this.
- That's right, kid. That's right.
www.tvsubtitles.net